[{
	"question": "When does India celebrate Independence Day?",
	"options": [
		"A. 15th August", 
		"B. 2nd October", 
		"C. 26th January", 
		"D. 4th July"],
	"answer": "A. 15th August"
},
{
	"question": "Nobel prize is awarded for which of the following disciplines?",
	"options": [
		"A. Literature, peace and economics", 
		"B. Medicine or Physiology",
		"C. Chemistry and Physics", 
		"D. All the above"],
	"answer": "D. All the above"
},
{
	"question": "Who had an explosive idea and first patented DYNAMITE?",
	"options": 
	[
		"A. J.R.Gluber", 
		"B. A.Novel", 
		"C. G.Fawks", 
		"D. W.Bickword"
	],
	"answer": "B. A.Novel"
},
{
	"question": "Helicopter was invented by?",
	"options": [
		"A. Drinker", 
		"B. Cockrell", 
		"C. Copernius", 
		"D. Broquet"],
	"answer": "D. Broquet"
},
{
	"question": "Who is the english physicist responsible for the (Big Bang Theory)?",
	"options": [
		"A. Albert Einstein", 
		"B. Michael Skube", 
		"C. George Gamow", 
		"D. Roger Penrose"],
	"answer": "C. George Gamow"
},
{
	"question": "What is the full form of GDP?",
	"options": [
		"A. Gross Domestic Product", 
		"B. Global Domestic Ratio", 
		"C. Gross depository Ratio", 
		"D. None of the above"],
	"answer": "A. Gross Domestic Product"
},
{
	"question": "As per a latest report by Brand Finance 2019, which is the India's most valuable brand?",
	"options": [
		"A. Reliance", 
		"B. Tata Group", 
		"C. State Bank of India", 
		"D. Flipkart"],
	"answer": "B. Tata Group"
},
{
	"question": "The minimum forest cover to maintain ecological balance in the plain is?",
	"options": [
		"A. 25%", 
		"B. 33%", 
		"C. 40%", 
		"D. 50%"],
	"answer": "B. 33%"
},
{
	"question": "'LIBRA' an alternative of existing cryptocurrency like bitcoin is being developed by?",
	"options": [
		"A. Facebook", 
		"B. Google", 
		"C. Microsoft", 
		"D. None of the above"],
	"answer": "A. Facebook"
},
{
	"question": "Epsom(England) is the place associated with?",
	"options": [
		"A. Snooker", 
		"B. shooting", 
		"C. polo", 
		"D. Horse racing"],
	"answer": "D. Horse racing"
},
{
	"question": "Headquater of International Olympic Committee is situated at?",
	"options": [
		"A. Athens", 
		"B. Lausanne", 
		"C. Dubai", 
		"D. None of the above"],
	"answer": "B. Lausanne"
},
{
	"question": "__________ is the process of dividing the disk into tracks and sectors?",
	"options": [
		"A. Tracking", 
		"B. Formatting", 
		"C. Crashing", 
		"D. Alloting"],
	"answer": "B. Formatting"
},
{
	"question": "Hydrogen bomb is based on the principle of?",
	"options": ["A.Nuclear fission", 
		"B. Natural radioactivity", 
		"C. Artificial radioactivity", 
		"D. Nuclear fusion"],
	"answer": "D. Nuclear fusion"
},
{
	"question": "Garampani Sanctuary is locate in which of the following places?",
	"options": ["A. Junagarh, Gujarat", 
		"B. Kohima, Nagaland", 
		"C. Diphu, Assam", 
		"D. Gangtok, Sikkim"],
	"answer": "C. Diphu, Assam"
},
{
	"question": "Entomology studies what?",
	"options": ["A. Behavior of human beings",
		"B. Insects",
		"C. The origin and history of technical and scientific terms",
		"D. The formation of rocks"],
	"answer": "B. Insects"
},
{
	"question": "Galileo was an astronomer who",
	"options": ["A. Developed the telescope",
		"B. Discovered four satellites of Jupiter",
		"C. discovered that the movement of pendulum produces a regular time measurement",
		"D. All the above"],
	"answer": "B. Discovered four satellites of Jupiter"
},
{
	"question": "Who is the father of geometry?",
	"options": ["A. Aristotle",
		"B. Euclid",
		"C. Pythagoras",
		"D. Kepler"],
	"answer": "B. Euclid"
},
{
	"question": "The working priciple of the Washing machine is?",
	"options": ["A. Reverse osmosis",
		"B. Diffusion",
		"C. Dialysis",
		"D. Centrifugation"],
	"answer": "D. centrifugation"
},
{
	"question": "Who is the current chief of the world bank group?",
	"options": ["A. Donald Tusk",
		"B. David Malpass",
		"C. Christine Lagarde",
		"D. Jim Yong Kim"],
	"answer": "B. David Malpass"
},
{
	"question": "Ms-Word is an example of?",
	"options": ["A. An operating system",
		"B. A processing device",
		"C. Application software",
		"D. An input device"],
	"answer": "C. Application software"
},
{
	"question": "Who was associated with the creation of pentium chip?",
	"options": ["A. Arun Netravalli",
		"B. Sabeer Bhatia",
		"C. Vinod Dham",
		"D. Vijay Dham"],
	"answer": "C. Vinod Dham"
},
{
	"question": "Ctrl,Shift and Alt are called ___________ keys?",
	"options": ["A. Modifier",
		"B. Function",
		"C. Aphabetical",
		"D. Adjustment"],
	"answer": "A. Modifier"
},
{
	"question": "Which is the first search engine of the internet?",
	"options": ["A. Yahoo",
		"B. Wais",
		"C. Archie",
		"D. Mozilla"],
	"answer": "C. Archie"
},
{
	"question": "In a Database Management System(DBMS) the content and the location of data is identified by ?",
	"options": ["A. Subdata",
		"B. Sequence Data",
		"C. Beta Data",
		"D. Meta Data"],
	"answer": "D. Meta Data"
},
{
	"question": "'.MOV' extensions refer to which kind of file?",
	"options": ["A. Image file",
		"B. Movie File",
		"C. Audio File",
		"D. ZIP File"],
	"answer": "B. Movie File"
},
{
	"question": "Who wrote the famous poem 'The Charge of the Light Brigade'?",
	"options": ["A. Lord Alfred Tennyson",
		"B. Christopher Marlowe",
		"C. Johannes Gutenberg",
		"D. Rene Descartes"],
	"answer": "A. Lord Alfred Tennyson"
},
{
	"question": "Who founded Indian National Army(INA)?",
	"options": ["A. Netaji Subhas Chandra Bose",
		"B. Mohan Singh",
		"C. Rash Behari Bose",
		"D. Jatridranath Mukherjee"],
	"answer": "B. Mohan Singh"
},
{
	"question": "The Indian, who holds the pride of beating the computers in mathematical wizard is?",
	"options": ["A. Shakuntala Devi",
		"B. Raja Ramanna",
		"C. Ramanujam",
		"D. Rina Panigrahi"],
	"answer": "A. Shakuntala Devi"
},
{
	"question": "J.B. Dunlop is popular for which of the following inventions?",
	"options": ["A. Model airplanes",
		"B. Pneumatic rubber tire",
		"C. Rubber boot",
		"D. Automobile wheel rim"],
	"answer": "B. Pneumatic rubber tire"
}
]
